<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Coronavirus App</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Android Studio</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="start">START</string>
    <string name="pause">PAUSE</string>
    <string name="what_is_the_source_of_the_virus">What is the source of the virus?</string>
    <string name="SourceOfCovid">Coronaviruses are a large family of viruses. Some cause illness in people, and others, such as canine and feline coronaviruses, only infect animals. \n\nRarely, animal coronaviruses that infect animals have emerged to infect people and can spread between people. \n\nThis is suspected to have occurred for the virus that causes COVID-19. Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS) and Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS) are two other examples of coronaviruses that originated from animals and then spread to people.</string>
    <string name="how_does_the_virus_spread">How does the virus spread?</string>
    <string name="HowCovidSpreads">This virus was first detected in Wuhan City, Hubei Province, China. The first infections were linked to a live animal market, but the virus is now spreading from person-to-person. It’s important to note that person-to-person spread can happen on a continuum. \n\nSome viruses are highly contagious (like measles), while other viruses are less so. The virus that causes COVID-19 seems to be spreading easily and sustainably in the community (“community spread”) in some affected geographic areas.</string>
    <string name="can_someone_with_covid_19_spread_the_illness">Can someone with COVID-19 spread the illness?</string>
    <string name="SpreadCovid">The virus that causes COVID-19 is spreading from person-to-person. Someone who is actively sick with COVID-19 can spread the illness to others. That is why CDC recommends that these patients be isolated either in the hospital or at home (depending on how sick they are) until they are better and no longer pose a risk of infecting others. \n\nHow long someone is actively sick can vary so the decision on when to release someone from isolation is made on a case-by-case basis in consultation with doctors, infection prevention and control experts, and public health officials and involves considering specifics of each situation including disease severity, illness signs and symptoms, and results of laboratory testing for that patient.</string>
    <string name="spread_the_illness">Can someone who has been Quarantined still spread the illness?</string>
    <string name="SomeoneWhoHasBeen">Quarantine means separating a person or group of people who have been exposed to a contagious disease but have not developed illness (symptoms) from others who have not been exposed, in order to prevent the possible spread of that disease. \n\nQuarantine is usually established for the incubation period of the communicable disease, which is the span of time during which people have developed illness after exposure. \n\nFor COVID-19, the period of quarantine is 14 days from the last date of exposure, because 14 days is the longest incubation period seen for similar coronaviruses. Someone who has been released from COVID-19 quarantine is not considered a risk for spreading the virus to others because they have not developed illness during the incubation period.</string>
    <string name="frozen_food">Can COVID-19 be spread through food including refrigerated and frozen food?</string>
    <string name="Frozen_temperatures">Coronaviruses are generally thought to be spread from person-to-person through respiratory droplets. Currently there is no evidence to support transmission of COVID-19 associated with food. \n\nBefore preparing or eating food it is important to always wash your hands with soap and water for 20 seconds for general food safety. Throughout the day wash your hands after blowing your nose, coughing or sneezing, or going to the bathroom. \n\nIt may be possible that a person can get COVID-19 by touching a surface or object that has the virus on it and then touching their own mouth, nose, or possibly their eyes, but this is not thought to be the main way the virus spreads. \n\nIn general, because of poor survivability of these coronaviruses on surfaces, there is likely very low risk of spread from food products or packaging that are shipped over a period of days or weeks at ambient, refrigerated, or frozen temperatures.</string>
    <string name="outbreak">Will warm weather stop the outbreak of COVID-19 outbreak?</string>
    <string name="it_ongoing">It is not yet known whether weather and temperature impact the spread of COVID-19. Some other viruses, like the common cold and flu, spread more during cold weather months but that does not mean it is impossible to become sick with these viruses during other months. \n\nAt this time, it is not known whether the spread of COVID-19 will decrease when weather becomes warmer. There is much more to learn about the transmissibility, severity, and other features associated with COVID-19 and investigations are ongoing.</string>
    <string name="what_is_community_spread">What is Community spread?</string>
    <string name="they_became_infected">Community spread means people have been infected with the virus in an area, including some who are not sure how or where they became infected.</string>
    <string name="about_covid_19">About COVID-19</string>
    <string name="how_to_protect_yourself">How to Protect Yourself</string>
    <string name="how_it_spreads">How It Spreads</string>
    <string name="symptoms_testing"><![CDATA[Symptoms & Testing]]></string>
    <string name="misinformation">Misinformation</string>
    <string name="the_basics">The Basics</string>
    <string name="misinfo">Misinformation</string>
    <string name="how_can_i_help_protect_myself">How can I help protect myself?</string>
    <string name="what_to_do">What to do if I come in close contact with someone who has COVID-19</string>
    <string name="facemasks_to_prevent_covid_19">Does the CDC recommend the use of facemasks to prevent COVID-19?</string>
    <string name="china">Am I at risk for COVID-19 from a package/product shipping from China?</string>
    <string name="covid_19_can_cause">What are the symptoms and complications that COVID-19 can cause?</string>
    <string name="tested_for_covid_19">Should I be tested for COVID-19?</string>
    <string name="Covid_19">Call your healthcare professional if you feel sick with fever, cough, or difficulty breathing, and have been in close contact with a person known to have COVID-19, or if you live in or have recently traveled from an area with ongoing spread of COVID-19. Your healthcare professional will work with your state’s public health department and CDC to determine if you need to be tested for COVID-19.</string>
    <string name="how_is_a_person_tested_for_covid_19">How is a person tested for COVID-19?</string>
    <string name="weekends_holidays">State and local health departments who have identified a person under investigation (PUI) should immediately notify CDC’s Emergency Operations Center (EOC) to report the PUI and determine whether testing for COVID-19 at CDC is indicated. The EOC will assist local/state health departments to collect, store, and ship specimens appropriately to CDC, including during afterhours or on weekends/holidays.</string>
    <string name="positive">Can a person test negative and later positive for COVID-19?</string>
    <string name="ill">In the early stages of infection, it is possible the virus will not be detected. For COVID-19, a negative test result for a sample collected while a person has symptoms likely means that the COVID-19 virus is not causing their current illness.</string>
    <string name="stig">Why might someone blame or avoid individuals and groups (create stigma) because of COVID-19?</string>
    <string name="problem">People may be worried or anxious about friends and relatives who are living in or visiting areas where COVID-19 is spreading. Some people are worried about the disease. Fear and anxiety can lead to social stigma, for example, towards Chinese or other Asian Americans or people who were in quarantine. \n\nStigma is discrimination against an identifiable group of people, a place, or a nation. Stigma is associated with a lack of knowledge about how COVID-19 spreads, a need to blame someone, fears about disease and death, and gossip that spreads rumors and myths. \n\nStigma hurts everyone by creating more fear or anger towards ordinary people instead of the disease that is causing the problem.</string>
    <string name="related_to_covid_19">How can people help stop stigma related to COVID-19?</string>
    <string name="help_stop_stigma">People can fight stigma and help, not hurt, others by providing social support. Counter stigma by learning and sharing facts. Communicating the facts that viruses do not target specific racial or ethnic groups and how COVID-19 actually spreads can help stop stigma.</string>
    <string name="wash">1. Avoid close contact with people who are sick. \n2. Avoid touching your eyes, nose, and mouth. \n3. Stay home when you are sick. \n4. Cover your cough or sneeze with a tissue, then throw the tissue in the trash. \n5. Clean and disinfect frequently touched objects and surfaces using a regular household cleaning spray or wipe. \n6. Wash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds, especially after going to the bathroom; before eating; and after blowing your nose, coughing, or sneezing. \n\nIf soap and water are not readily available, use an alcohol-based hand sanitizer with at least 60% alcohol. Always wash hands with soap and water if hands are visibly dirty</string>
    <string name="cure_for_covid_19">Is there a cure for COVID-19?</string>
    <string name="organ_functions">There is no specific antiviral treatment recommended for COVID-19. People with COVID-19 should receive supportive care to help relieve symptoms. For severe cases, treatment should include care to support vital organ functions.</string>
    <string name="help">Stay home except to get medical care People who are mildly ill with COVID-19 are able to isolate at home during their illness. You should restrict activities outside your home, except for getting medical care. \n\nDo not go to work, school, or public areas. \nAvoid using public transportation, ride-sharing, or taxis. \n\nSeparate yourself from other people and animals in your home People: As much as possible, you should stay in a specific room and away from other people in your home. Also, you should use a separate bathroom, if available. \n\nAnimals: \nYou should restrict contact with pets and other animals while you are sick with COVID-19, just like you would around other people. Although there have not been reports of pets or other animals becoming sick with COVID-19, it is still recommended that people sick with COVID-19 limit contact with animals until more information is known about the virus. When possible, have another member of your household care for your animals while you are sick. \n\nIf you are sick with COVID-19, avoid contact with your pet, including petting, snuggling, being kissed or licked, and sharing food. If you must care for your pet or be around animals while you are sick, wash your hands before and after you interact with pets and wear a facemask. \n\nCall ahead before visiting your doctor If you have a medical appointment, call the healthcare provider and tell them that you have or may have COVID-19. This will help the healthcare provider’s office take steps to keep other people from getting infected or exposed. \n\nWear a facemask \nYou should wear a facemask when you are around other people (e.g., sharing a room or vehicle) or pets and before you enter a healthcare provider’s office. If you are not able to wear a facemask (for example, because it causes trouble breathing), then people who live with you should not stay in the same room with you, or they should wear a facemask if they enter your room. \n\nCover your coughs and sneezes \nCover your mouth and nose with a tissue when you cough or sneeze. Throw used tissues in a lined trash can. Immediately wash your hands with soap and water for at least 20 seconds or, if soap and water are not available, clean your hands with an alcohol-based hand sanitizer that contains at least 60% alcohol. \n\nClean your hands often \nWash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds, especially after blowing your nose, coughing, or sneezing; going to the bathroom; and before eating or preparing food. If soap and water are not readily available, use an alcohol-based hand sanitizer with at least 60% alcohol, covering all surfaces of your hands and rubbing them together until they feel dry. Soap and water are the best option if hands are visibly dirty. \n\nAvoid touching your eyes, nose, and mouth with unwashed hands. \nAvoid sharing personal household items You should not share dishes, drinking glasses, cups, eating utensils, towels, or bedding with other people or pets in your home. \nAfter using these items, they should be washed thoroughly with soap and water. Clean all “high-touch” surfaces everyday High touch surfaces include counters, tabletops, doorknobs, bathroom fixtures, toilets, phones, keyboards, tablets, and bedside tables. \n\nAlso, clean any surfaces that may have blood, stool, or body fluids on them. Use a household cleaning spray or wipe, according to the label instructions. \nLabels contain instructions for safe and effective use of the cleaning product including precautions you should take when applying the product, such as wearing gloves and making sure you have good ventilation during use of the product. \n\nMonitor your symptoms Seek prompt medical attention if your illness is worsening (e.g., difficulty breathing). \nThese steps will help the healthcare provider’s office to keep other people in the office or waiting room from getting infected or exposed. \nAsk your healthcare provider to call the local or state health department. \nPersons who are placed under active monitoring or facilitated self-monitoring should follow instructions provided by their local health department or occupational health professionals, as appropriate. \n\nIf you have a medical emergency and need to call 911, notify the dispatch personnel that you have, or are being evaluated for COVID-19. If possible, put on a facemask before emergency medical services arrive. \n\nDiscontinuing home isolation Patients with confirmed COVID-19 should remain under home isolation precautions until the risk of secondary transmission to others is thought to be low. The decision to discontinue home isolation precautions should be made on a case-by-case basis, in consultation with healthcare providers and state and local health departments.</string>
    <string name="what_is_a_novel_cornavirus_covid_19">What is a novel cornavirus/COVID-19?</string>
    <string name="coronavirus_diagnosis">A novel coronavirus is a new coronavirus that has not been previously identified. The virus causing coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), is not the same as the coronaviruses that commonly circulate among humans and cause mild illness, like the common cold. \n\nA diagnosis with other coronaviruses is not the same as a COVID-19 diagnosis. Patients with COVID-19 will be evaluated and cared for differently than patients with common coronavirus diagnosis.</string>
    <string name="why_is_the_disease_being_called_covid_19">Why is the disease being called COVID-19?</string>
    <string name="disease">On February 11, 2020 the World Health Organization announced an official name for the disease that is causing the 2019 novel coronavirus outbreak, first identified in Wuhan China. The new name of this disease is coronavirus disease 2019, abbreviated as COVID-19. \n\nIn COVID-19, ‘CO’ stands for ‘corona,’ ‘VI’ for ‘virus,’ and ‘D’ for disease. Formerly, this disease was referred to as “2019 novel coronavirus” or “2019-nCoV”. There are many types of human coronaviruses including some that commonly cause mild upper-respiratory tract illnesses. COVID-19 is a new disease, caused be a novel (or new) coronavirus that has not previously been seen in humans. \n\nThe name of this disease was selected following the World Health Organization (WHO) best practice for naming of new human infectious diseases.</string>
    <string name="treating_covid_19">Are antibiotics effective in preventing or treating COVID-19?</string>
    <string name="bacterial_infection">No. Antibiotics do not work against viruses, they only work on bacterial infections. COVID-19 is caused by a virus, so antibiotics do not work. Antibiotics should not be used as a means of prevention or treatment of COVID-19. They should only be used as directed by a physician to treat a bacterial infection.</string>
    <string name="is_there_something_i_should_not_do">Is there something I should NOT do?</string>
    <string name="health_care_provider">The following measures ARE NOT effective against COVID-2019 and can be harmful: \n\n Smoking \n Taking traditional herbal remedies \n Wearing multiple masks \n Taking self-medication such as antibiotics \n\nIn any case, if you have fever, cough and difficulty breathing seek medical care early to reduce the risk of developing a more severe infection and be sure to share your recent travel history with your health care provider.</string>
    <string name="cold_weather_and_snow_cannot_kill_the_new_coronavirus">Cold weather and snow CANNOT kill the new coronavirus.</string>
    <string name="water">There is no reason to believe that cold weather can kill the new coronavirus or other diseases. The normal human body temperature remains around 36.5°C to 37°C, regardless of the external temperature or weather. The most effective way to protect yourself against the new coronavirus is by frequently cleaning your hands with alcohol-based hand rub or washing them with soap and water.</string>
    <string name="the_new_coronavirus_disease">Taking a hot bath does not prevent the new coronavirus disease</string>
    <string name="eyes_mouth_and_nose">Taking a hot bath will not prevent you from catching COVID-19. Your normal body temperature remains around 36.5°C to 37°C, regardless of the temperature of your bath or shower. Actually, taking a hot bath with extremely hot water can be harmful, as it can burn you. The best way to protect yourself against COVID-19 is by frequently cleaning your hands. By doing this you eliminate viruses that may be on your hands and avoid infection that coud occur by then touching your eyes, mouth, and nose.</string>
    <string name="mosquito_bites">The new coronavirus CANNOT be transmitted through mosquito bites.</string>
    <string name="sneez">To date there has been no information nor evidence to suggest that the new coronavirus could be transmitted by mosquitoes. The new coronavirus is a respiratory virus which spreads primarily through droplets generated when an infected person coughs or sneezes, or through droplets of saliva or discharge from the nose. To protect yourself, clean your hands frequently with an alcohol-based hand rub or wash them with soap and water. Also, avoid close contact with anyone who is coughing and sneezing.</string>
    <string name="are_hand_dryers">Are hand dryers effective in killing the new coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="warm_air_dryer">No. Hand dryers are not effective in killing the 2019-nCoV. To protect yourself against the new coronavirus, you should frequently clean your hands with an alcohol-based hand rub or wash them with soap and water. Once your hands are cleaned, you should dry them thoroughly by using paper towels or a warm air dryer.</string>
    <string name="lamp_kill_the_new_coronavirus">Can an ultraviolet disinfection lamp kill the new coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="cause_skin_irritation">UV lamps should not be used to sterilize hands or other areas of skin as UV radiation can cause skin irritation.</string>
    <string name="how_new_coronavirus">How effective are thermal scanners in detecting people infected with the new coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="develop_a_fever">Thermal scanners are effective in detecting people who have developed a fever (i.e. have a higher than normal body temperature) because of infection with the new coronavirus. However, they cannot detect people who are infected but are not yet sick with fever. This is because it takes between 2 and 10 days before people who are infected become sick and develop a fever.</string>
    <string name="body_kill_the_new_coronavirus">Can spraying alcohol or chlorine all over your body kill the new coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="recommendations">No. Spraying alcohol or chlorine all over your body will not kill viruses that have already entered your body. Spraying such substances can be harmful to clothes or mucous membranes (i.e. eyes, mouth). Be aware that both alcohol and chlorine can be useful to disinfect surfaces, but they need to be used under appropriate recommendations.</string>
    <string name="coronavirus_2019_ncov">Can pets at home spread the new coronavirus (COVID-19)?</string>
    <string name="pets_and_humans">At present, there is no evidence that companion animals/pets such as dogs or cats can be infected with the new coronavirus. However, it is always a good idea to wash your hands with soap and water after contact with pets. This protects you against various common bacteria such as E.coli and Salmonella that can pass between pets and humans.</string>
    <string name="do_vaccines_against_pneumonia_protect_">Do vaccines against pneumonia protect you against the new coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="protect_your_health">No. Vaccines against pneumonia, such as pneumococcal vaccine and Haemophilus influenza type B (Hib) vaccine, do not provide protection against the new coronavirus. The virus is so new and different that it needs its own vaccine. Researchers are trying to develop a vaccine against 2019-nCoV, and WHO is supporting their efforts. Although these vaccines are not effective against 2019-nCoV, vaccination against respiratory illnesses is highly recommended to protect your health.</string>
    <string name="infection_with_the_new_coronavirus">Can regularly rinsing your nose with saline help prevent infection with the new coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="respiratory_infections">No. There is no evidence that regularly rinsing the nose with saline has protected people from infection with the new coronavirus. There is some limited evidence that regularly rinsing nose with saline can help people recover more quickly from the common cold. However, regularly rinsing the nose has not been shown to prevent respiratory infections.</string>
    <string name="the_new_coronavirus">Can eating garlic help prevent infection with the new coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="people_from_the_new_coronavirus">Garlic is a healthy food that may have some antimicrobial properties. However, there is no evidence from the current outbreak that eating garlic has protected people from the new coronavirus.</string>
    <string name="basic">The Basics</string>
    <string name="facemasks">CDC does not recommend that people who are well wear a facemask to protect themselves from respiratory diseases, including COVID-19. Facemasks should be used by people who show symptoms of COVID-19 to help prevent the spread of the disease to others. The use of facemasks is also crucial for health workers and people who are taking care of someone in close settings (at home or in a health care facility).</string>
    <string name="imported_goods">There is still a lot that is unknown about the newly emerged COVID-19 and how it spreads. Two other coronaviruses have emerged previously to cause severe illness in people (MERS-CoV and SARS-CoV). The virus that causes COVID-19 is more genetically related to SARS-CoV than MERS-CoV, but both are betacoronaviruses with their origins in bats. \n\nWhile we don’t know for sure that this virus will behave the same way as SARS-CoV and MERS-CoV, we can use the information gained from both of these earlier coronaviruses to guide us. In general, because of poor survivability of these coronaviruses on surfaces, there is likely very low risk of spread from products or packaging that are shipped over a period of days or weeks at ambient temperatures. \n\nCoronaviruses are generally thought to be spread most often by respiratory droplets. Currently there is no evidence to support transmission of COVID-19 associated with imported goods and there have not been any cases of COVID-19 in the United States associated with imported goods.</string>
    <string name="shortness_of_breath">Reported illnesses have ranged from mild symptoms to severe illness and death for confirmed coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) cases. \n\nThe following symptoms may appear 2"-"14 days after exposure: \n Fever \n Cough \n Shortness of breath\n</string>

    <string name="hand_wash_timer">Hand Wash Timer</string>
    <string name="source"><![CDATA[Source: www.cdc.gov & www.who.int]]></string>
    <string name="remember_to_wash_your_hands">REMEMBER TO WASH YOUR HANDS</string>
    <string name="check_for_updates">Check for Updates</string>
    <string name="support_dev">Support Developer</string>


</resources>
